<Table>
<Row><Cell>game_over_basicTraining</Cell><Cell>You've lost the trust of Sir Radzig.</Cell><Cell>你失去了拉德季大人的信任</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_conquest_fled</Cell><Cell>Without your help, Istvan won the Battle of Talmberg.</Cell><Cell>因为没有你的支援，伊斯特万打赢了塔尔木堡战役</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_conquest_follow_capon</Cell><Cell>Without getting help, your father died.</Cell><Cell>你的父亲因为无助而死</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_counteroffensive_reinforcements</Cell><Cell>You didn't get the reinforcements to Vranik from Talmberg.</Cell><Cell>你没有从塔尔木堡取得到弗拉尼克的援军</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_bleeding</Cell><Cell>You have bled to death.</Cell><Cell>你流血至死</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_collision</Cell><Cell>You have died.</Cell><Cell>你死了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_fall</Cell><Cell>You have fallen to your death.</Cell><Cell>你摔死了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_poison</Cell><Cell>You have been poisoned.</Cell><Cell>你中毒了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_scripted_hit</Cell><Cell>You were murdered under unforseen circumstances.</Cell><Cell>你被谋杀了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_self_harm</Cell><Cell>You have died by your own hand.</Cell><Cell>你把自己杀死了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_by_starving</Cell><Cell>You have starved to death. </Cell><Cell>你饥饿至死</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_in_combat</Cell><Cell>You have died in combat.</Cell><Cell>你血战至死</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_in_jail</Cell><Cell>You have died in jail.</Cell><Cell>你死于狱中</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_died_unknown</Cell><Cell>You have died.</Cell><Cell>你死了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_E3_lost</Cell><Cell>You have lost the battle.</Cell><Cell>你输掉了战斗</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_E3_win</Cell><Cell>You are victorious!</Cell><Cell>你胜利了！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_escape_skalitz</Cell><Cell>You've been hit by a stray Cuman arrow.</Cell><Cell>你被库曼人的流矢射中了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_escape_talmberk</Cell><Cell>Robard is really angry at you right now.</Cell><Cell>罗巴德现在对你很生气</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_finished</Cell><Cell>Game finished</Cell><Cell>游戏结束</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_killed_by_zmola</Cell><Cell>Zmola killed you while you were unconscious.</Cell><Cell>莫拉在你失去意识的时候把你杀了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_killed_while_unconscious</Cell><Cell>You were killed while unconscious.</Cell><Cell>你失去意识的时候被杀死了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_lostBattle</Cell><Cell>You lost the battle.</Cell><Cell>你输掉了战斗</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_night_rescue_crime</Cell><Cell>You committed treachery!</Cell><Cell>你竟背信弃义！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_night_rescue_ran_away</Cell><Cell>Young Lord Capon died while attempting to rescue the hostages.</Cell><Cell>少主卡蓬在你试图营救人质时战死了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_nights_watch</Cell><Cell>You've been kicked out of the Bailiff's service for incompetence.</Cell><Cell>你因为无能而被逐出了执政官的军队</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_ptacek_bled</Cell><Cell>Capon lost 5 pints of blood. His goose is cooked.</Cell><Cell>卡蓬流失了5品脱的血，他现在情况不太妙</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_revelation_killing_inquisitor_text</Cell><Cell>Murdering a servant of God is a most heinous crime! You tried to flee, but they soon caught up with you. Sir Radzig turned his back on you and you were hanged for your crime. Johanka was convicted of heresy and died as a result of her punishment.</Cell><Cell>谋杀上帝的仆人是最严重的罪！你尝试逃跑，但很快就被抓住了。拉德季大人也保不了你，你被判处绞刑，乔汉卡因异端言论也被处死了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_revelation_killing_inquisitor_undercover_seen_text</Cell><Cell>You were seen killing the Inquisitor and the law soon caught up with you. Sir Radzig turned his back on you and you were hanged for your crime.</Cell><Cell>你杀死审判官的行为被发现了，拉德季大人也保不了你，你被判处绞刑</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_revelation_speking_heresy_text</Cell><Cell>You died after your tongue was cut out for heretical speeches. Johanka was also convicted of heresy and suffered the same fate.</Cell><Cell>在你的舌头因为异端言论被扯掉后，你也死了。乔汉卡也被判处异端罪，并有相同的下场</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_run</Cell><Cell>A village lad like you has no chance of defeating the fearsome Cumans. Better to run and save your skin.</Cell><Cell>一个像你一样的乡下小子可不可能打败武装到牙齿的库曼战士，你最好还是逃命吧</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_simek_text</Cell><Cell>Samuel died.</Cell><Cell>塞穆尔死了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_tereza_escape</Cell><Cell>You were hit by a stray Cuman arrow and died while trying to flee.</Cell><Cell>你被一支库曼人的流箭射中了，然后你在逃亡的途中死了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_tereza_prison</Cell><Cell>You've been executed for your grave crimes. May God have mercy on your sinful soul.</Cell><Cell>你因为你严重的罪行而被处死了，希望上帝能宽恕你罪恶的灵魂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_test</Cell><Cell>TEST</Cell><Cell>TEST</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>game_over_thank_you</Cell><Cell>Thank you for playing!</Cell><Cell>感谢游玩！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1050_G8Y7</Cell><Cell>Replace</Cell><Cell>替换</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1051_XHhc</Cell><Cell>Bury</Cell><Cell>埋</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1210_8zxc</Cell><Cell>Colour the water</Cell><Cell>把水染红。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc2_sch2_GhfW_e1508_DCgh</Cell><Cell>Throw</Cell><Cell>扔臭鸡蛋</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e20_O9rb</Cell><Cell>Travelling the roads in the province is hazardous - merchants are afraid even to stick their noses out of the inns, visiting relatives in neighbouring villages is a life or death gamble and folk living in remote farmsteads sleep with axes under their pillows. Behind any oak or ash along the wayside, there may be a ruthless bandit lying in wait, or even a poor student, who has drunk away his last Groschen and entered the spirit of these lawless times. Either way, the victim is lucky to lose only his purse, and not his head. </Cell><Cell>在省内道路上旅行是不安全的-商人们都不敢踏出旅馆半步，到邻近的村子亲戚家里串门是个生死决断，住在偏远农庄的人们睡觉时枕头底下总要藏把斧头。在道路两侧的树林或废墟后面，十有八九会藏着一个无法无天的歹徒，亦或是一个穷苦的学生，喝得身无分文，沦为匪盗之流。不管是谁来打劫，丢了钱包的受害者，没把头也一并让人家拿走，就算是不幸中的万幸。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e21_Nuca</Cell><Cell>You can start dealing with the danger on the roads by talking to Sir Radzig after completing the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Baptism of Fire&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. Shortly after this point in the story, Sir Radzig will be found at the viewing point over Talmberg, and later at Pirkstein Castle in Rattay. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. This assignment may be temporarily unavailable during the military operations towards the end of the main storyline, or may halt progress in the story for a while. </Cell><Cell>你可以在完成主线任务以后，与拉德季大人交谈，开始着手扫清道路上的危险。 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt; 战火洗礼 &amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. 在故事情节发展到这一节点后，拉德季大人会出现在塔尔木堡的观景台上，之后会在拉泰的皮克斯坦城堡。如果你不知道该去哪儿找他，注意 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; 图标。这个任务会在主线故事临近结束时的战斗阶段暂时不可接纳，若已接受任务，则其进展将会搁置一段时间。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e23_kzPo</Cell><Cell>Travelling the roads in the province is hazardous - merchants are afraid even to stick their noses out of the inns, visiting relatives in neighbouring villages is a life or death gamble and folk living in remote farmsteads sleep with axes under their pillows. Behind any oak or ash along the wayside, there may be a ruthless bandit lying in wait, or even a poor student, who has drunk away his last Groschen and entered the spirit of these lawless times. Either way, the victim is lucky to lose only his purse, and not his head. </Cell><Cell>在省内道路上旅行是不安全的-商人们都不敢踏出旅馆半步，到邻近的村子亲戚家里串门是个生死决断，住在偏远农庄的人们睡觉时枕头底下总要藏把斧头。在道路两侧的树林或废墟后面，十有八九会藏着一个无法无天的歹徒，亦或是一个穷苦的学生，喝得身无分文，沦为匪盗之流。不管是谁来打劫，丢了钱包的受害者，没把头也一并让人家拿走，就算是不幸中的万幸。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc3_sch8_9v0p_e24_xgFu</Cell><Cell>You can see Sir Radzig and begin dealing with the dangers lurking on the provincial roads. He can usually be found at Pirkstein Castle in Rattay. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. This assignment may be temporarily unavailable during the military operations towards the end of the main storyline, or may halt progress in the story for a while. </Cell><Cell>你可以去找拉德季大人，开始着手扫清道路上的危险。你通常可以在皮科斯坦城堡找到他，如果你不知道该去哪儿找他，注意 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc3Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;图标。这个任务会在主线故事临近结束时的战斗阶段暂时不可接纳，若已接受任务，则其进展将会搁置一段时间。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch1_AMrB_e3098_CkTL</Cell><Cell>Talk to Johanka</Cell><Cell>找乔汉卡聊聊。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap_dlc4_sch15_0k9l_e13_o1c5</Cell><Cell>Once she goes into Skalitz, Theresa can't continue to pursue side quests and won't be able to save the survivors outside.</Cell><Cell>一旦她进入了斯卡里茨，特丽莎就无法继续她的支线任务了，而且还救不了外面的幸存者了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e2_Zpwe</Cell><Cell>Foe</Cell><Cell>敌人</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e3_4ZbU</Cell><Cell>Fight</Cell><Cell>参战</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e4_pPRz</Cell><Cell>Stop</Cell><Cell>停下</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e6_FZId</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>走为上策</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch20_Bmon_e8_evade</Cell><Cell>Evade</Cell><Cell>逃避</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap12_sch3_6Ntp_e1050_ShB2</Cell><Cell>You blacked out and have no idea how you got here.</Cell><Cell>你晕了过去，并且对你为什么到了这里毫无头绪。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C__sch0_kfJy_e117_T7YN</Cell><Cell>There's no time. You're under attack!</Cell><Cell>没时间了！你正在被攻击！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C__sch0_kfJy_e131_CFPj</Cell><Cell>You abandoned your lord and he died. For that you'll swing on the gallows.</Cell><Cell>你的主人因你弃主而死，为此你要上绞刑架吊死</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch1_oPBP_e1311_7rP3</Cell><Cell>Pick roses</Cell><Cell>摘玫瑰花</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch1_oPBP_e597_vKdO</Cell><Cell>Get into the bath dressed.</Cell><Cell>穿着衣服去洗澡</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch1_oPBP_e598_e1oH</Cell><Cell>Take off the clothes and get into the bath.</Cell><Cell>脱掉衣服去洗澡</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch2_dZo8_e1718_qbrs</Cell><Cell>A certain robber baron by the name of Wolflin of Kamberg has been pillaging farms in the fiefdom of Rattay with his band of renegades. The Lord of Rattay, Sir Hanush, takes a very dim view of his estates being ransacked, and so he's sent out a punitive expedition to deal with the outlaws. You are to take part.</Cell><Cell>一个名叫卡姆堡的沃尔弗林的贵族强盗带着一伙暴徒洗劫了拉泰的几处农场。拉泰的领主瀚纳什大人，对他的领地受到侵袭感到不满，派出一队人马讨伐这群法外之徒。你便是突击队的一员。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch2_dZo8_e1719_yQKd</Cell><Cell>Your corps is about to attack Wolflin's encampment. It will be a tough battle, because the enemy is expecting you and your forces are more or less matched. Arm yourself well and may God guide your hand!</Cell><Cell>你的部队即将进攻沃尔弗林的营地。这将会是一场恶战，因为敌人认为双方势均力敌。武装你自己，愿上帝指引你通向最终的胜利！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e1_FNiR</Cell><Cell>There's never a dull moment with the bold Sir Hans Capon. Before he can proceed with his knightly duties, he wants me to help him with a certain delicate matter of great urgency. </Cell><Cell>勇敢的汉斯卡蓬大人真是一刻都不会闲着呢。在他继续完成他的骑士职责之前，他想让我帮他完成某件微妙的事情，刻不容缓。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e11_pHxc</Cell><Cell>The beginning of a new adventure with Sir Hans is active at the end of the Capon quest line, culminating in the &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Robber Baron&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; assigment, which can be started after the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Questions and Answers.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; Capon, however, has no time for amorous adventures during the battles towards the end of the game, so you won't be able to accept the quest from him until the very end, when Sir Hans arrives at the camp by Neuhof. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc2Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon.</Cell><Cell>《花花公子》的内容会在完成所有汉斯·卡蓬少主的支线任务后开始。接着在主线任务 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Questions and Answers.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 结束后的支线任务 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Robber Baron&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 然而卡蓬少主在主线后期的战斗中无法去追求他的梦中情人，所以那时候除非玩到了最最最最后面的剧情，也就是卡蓬少主去了诺伊霍夫周围的营地，在此之前你将无法游玩此DLC的内容。不确定去哪里找到他？请留意 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc2Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;; 标志</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e13_J5OK</Cell><Cell>The beginning of a new adventure with Sir Hans is now active. All you have to do is go and talk to him. Capon, however, has no time for amorous adventures during the battles towards the end of the game, so you won't be able to accept the quest from him until the very end, when Sir Hans goes to the camp at Neuhof. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc2Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon.</Cell><Cell>《花花公子》的内容已经激活了。你现在只需要去和卡蓬少主对话。然而卡蓬少主在主线后期的战斗中无法去追求他的梦中情人，所以那时候除非玩到了最最最最后面的剧情，也就是卡蓬少主去了诺伊霍夫周围的营地，在此之前你将无法游玩此DLC的内容。不确定去哪里找到他？请留意 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc2Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;标志</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e2_Kw10</Cell><Cell>Knowing that Sir Hans has somewhat different priorities than the other local lords, it wouldn't be unreasonable to assume that a damsel is involved. After our last dramatic adventure at the bathhouse, I'm curious - and more than a little apprehensive - as to what his latest escapade will be all about.</Cell><Cell>我知道汉斯大人和当地的其他领主们关注的重点不太一样，所以我猜这件事跟一个姑娘有关也不是毫无依据的。上次我们在澡堂里的戏剧性的大冒险结束之后，我就很好奇——而且不止一丁点担忧——他的新冒险会是关于什么的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e2_NFgO</Cell><Cell>Wicked tongues say the heir to the Town of Rattay, young Sir Hans Capon, is an incorrigible seducer and whore-monger. A more charitable view is that he's just looking for love. The kind you can't buy at the bathhouse...</Cell><Cell>恶毒的传言都这么说：拉泰城的继承人，年轻的汉斯卡蓬大人是个无可救药的花花公子、一个皮条客。有道德的说法是，他只是在不断寻求真爱。但真爱是没法在澡堂里买到的……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e3_XzI6</Cell><Cell>You know the heir to the Town of Rattay, young Sir Hans Capon, well enough to realise that there's more than a little truth to the rumours that he's an incorrigible seducer and whore-monger. But then again, maybe he's just looking for love. The kind you can't buy at the bathhouse...</Cell><Cell>你跟拉泰城的继承人，年轻的汉斯卡蓬大人已经足够熟识了，因此你知道那些说他是个不可救药的花花公子和皮条客的流言其实并不是空穴来风。但是，也许他只是在寻找真爱呢。只是真爱是没法在澡堂里买到的……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e4_iPlE</Cell><Cell>You have yet to make the acquaintance of the bold Sir Hans Capon, but once you do, be prepared to get drawn into his amorous adventures. You, a common blacksmith's son, will become His Lordship's herald, his messenger of love!</Cell><Cell>你还没有和勇敢的汉斯卡蓬大人相熟，但是一旦你和他熟识了，你就得做好被拉进他的浪漫大冒险中去的准备。你，一个寻常的铁匠之子，要成为这领主大人的爱情信使了！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e6_YhfZ</Cell><Cell>You have a feeling that if you knew him better, you are very likely to get drawn into his amorous adventures. His Lordship's herald, his messenger of love - it has a ring to it!</Cell><Cell>你有种直觉：如果你跟他再熟一点，你就要被他拉进他的浪漫大冒险中了，作为这领主大人的爱情信使——听起来就有这种感觉！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap17_t1C_sch3_JglP_e9_SGAF</Cell><Cell>Sir Hans Capon, the rightful heir to the Town of Rattay, dedicates most of his time to educating himself in matters knightly. He excels at hunting, combat and horseriding... or so he believes. He hasn't mastered the nobel game of chess, or even the more common game of dice, and as for poetry recitation, the time has come for him to work on that, if he's to win the heart of the maiden of his dreams.</Cell><Cell>汉斯·卡蓬大人，卡泰城的合法继承人，一直都在受着骑士教育。他擅长打猎，战斗和骑马……至少他这么觉得。他一直不擅长贵族运动象棋，也不擅长平民运动骰子游戏，关于作诗，现在到了他练习这件事的时候了，看看他能不能借此赢得他梦中情人的心</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e23_l8le</Cell><Cell>Black clouds of strife are gathering, the thundering drums of war rumble across the land and the whole  kingdom awaits the next lightning bolt with bated breath. Not so the undaunted Sir Hanush, who decided to bolster morale with a regular tourney to keep his subjects fighting fit and distract them from the pervasive gloom. </Cell><Cell>黑云压城，角声满天，愈打惊雷，举国上下，兵凶战危。只有瀚纳仕大人仍是毫无惧色，他决意举办定期的比武大会，鼓舞军将斗志，训练兵士战力，缓解他们备战的压力。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e24_Edki</Cell><Cell>The tourney takes place every few days by the Upper Castle in Rattay. All types of melee weapons are permitted, and the contest is open to combatants from all walks of life, even a lowborn, uneducated misfit like you. Just go and ask Sir Hans Capon about it and he'll tell you all you need to know.</Cell><Cell>比武大会几日便会在拉泰上层城堡举办。没有武器限制，全民不分三六九等，皆可参与，甚至连你这种出身卑贱、不学无术的家伙都能参赛。去找汉斯·卡蓬少主，他会告诉你详细信息的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e26_cIeS</Cell><Cell>Black clouds of strife are gathering, the thundering drums of war rumble across the land and the whole  kingdom awaits the next lightning bolt with bated breath. Not so the undaunted Sir Hanush, who decided to bolster morale with a regular tourney to keep his subjects fighting fit and distract them from the pervasive gloom. </Cell><Cell>黑云压城，角声满天，愈打惊雷，举国上下，兵凶战危。只有瀚纳仕大人仍是毫无惧色，他决意举办定期的比武大会，鼓舞军将斗志，训练兵士战力，缓解他们备战的压力。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e27_dQji</Cell><Cell>The tourney takes place every few days by the Upper Castle in Rattay. All types of melee weapons are permitted, and the contest is open to combatants from all walks of life, even a lowborn, uneducated misfit like you. Young Sir Hans Capon will tell you all you need to know about it. Once you've become better acquainted with him, that is. </Cell><Cell>比武大会几日便会在拉泰上层城堡举办。没有武器限制，全民不分三六九等，皆可参与，甚至连你这种出身卑贱、不学无术的家伙都能参赛。去找汉斯·卡蓬少主，他会告诉你详细信息的。要是你了解他的话，自然就会去找他了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e30_5QY2</Cell><Cell>The tournament convened by Sir Hanush takes place once every seven days at Rattay Upper Castle. The aim of the tourney is to test the skill of combatants will all kinds of weapons. It's intended for commoners, so you can enrol too. </Cell><Cell>瀚纳什大人举办的比武大会在拉泰上层城堡每周举办一次。举办比武大会的目的是检验参赛人员对武器使用的能力。这是为平民准备的，所以你也可以参加</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e32_m7B8</Cell><Cell>After completing the side quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Next to Godliness&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; with Sir Hans, you can accept a new quest from him, which will launch an instance of the regular tournament. If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. If you've already progressed in the storyline as far as &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Epilogue&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, you won't be able to accept the quest from Capon and the Tournament will launch on its own. the tournament will not take place while Sir Hanush is at war. </Cell><Cell>在与汉斯卡蓬少主完成支线任务 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Next to Godliness&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 后，你可以从他那里接收一个新任务，这将马上开始一场常规比武。如果你不确定去哪里找他，你可以找找 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;. 标志。如果你的主线剧情已经推进到了 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Epilogue&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 你将无法去找卡蓬少主要这个任务，但比武大会将自动开始。在瀚纳什大人处于战争剧情的时候，比武大会不会举行</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e34_2Ipt</Cell><Cell>You can go and see Sir Hans and accept from him a new quest, which will launch a regular tournament. If you're not sure where to find Sir Hans, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. If you've already progressed in the storyline as far as &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Epilogue&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, you won't be able to accept the quest from Capon and the tournament will launch on its own. The tournament will not take place while Sir Hanush is at war. </Cell><Cell>你可以从卡蓬少主那里接收一个新任务，这将马上开始一场常规比武。如果你不确定去哪里找他，你可以找找 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlcTournamentOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; 标志。如果你的主线剧情已经推进到了 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Epilogue&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 你将无法去找卡蓬少主要这个任务，但比武大会将自动开始。在瀚纳什大人处于战争剧情的时候，比武大会不会举行</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap21_sch7_d5jy_e36_F5Dq</Cell><Cell>After launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; in Rattay, a tournament will be automatically launched every week at Rattay Upper Castle. The tournament will not take place, however, while Sir Hanush is at war. </Cell><Cell>在完成主线任务 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 后，一场比武大会将在拉泰上层城堡每周举行一次。在瀚纳什大人处于战争剧情的时候，比武大会不会举行</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e131_Qgwo</Cell><Cell>Quest started</Cell><Cell>任务开始</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e132_70UZ</Cell><Cell>Blessing of overseer</Cell><Cell>监工的祈祷</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e132_gMEy</Cell><Cell>Chasing Zmola</Cell><Cell>追踪莫拉</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap27_PxIe_sch0_c5YT_e132_H3Q2</Cell><Cell>Disappearance of Leshek</Cell><Cell>雷士克的消失</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e2_eyDY</Cell><Cell>Wayfarer</Cell><Cell>路人</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e4_dQKb</Cell><Cell>Examine</Cell><Cell>查看</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e5_yZbc</Cell><Cell>Ignore</Cell><Cell>无视</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e7_obSX</Cell><Cell>Stop  </Cell><Cell>停下</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap32_sch1_Yhte_e8_5efG</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>走为上策</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e52_pzSy</Cell><Cell>To your surprise, you've found there are some interesting papers amongst your things. Most likely they were concealed in the saddlebag of the horse you escaped from Skalitz on. It seems the men of the Talmberg garrison assumed they were yours and put them in your trunk. But how would a common blacksmith's son come by such documents? After all, you can't even read! The mysterious documents have an ancient seal that testifies to the noble and ancient origin of their author. </Cell><Cell>恭喜你在你的物品之中找到了一些有趣的文件。它们也许被放在你从斯卡里茨逃离时骑的马的鞍袋里。看起来塔尔木堡的守卫们以为这些是属于你的，所以把他们放进了你的箱子里。但是一个普通铁匠的儿子是怎么得到这种文件的？毕竟你字都不认识！这些神秘的文件上陈旧的密封证明它们的作者有着高贵而古老的出身</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e53_nsaj</Cell><Cell>You're not able to make any sense out of their content, but, luckily for you, you're not the first one to examine them. And whoever it was that read them, that learned person created a number of simple sketches based on their content, which look like descriptions of places where rare items of clothing and armour are hidden! You've put the papers safely away in your trunk, where they're waiting until you have time to study them more closely.</Cell><Cell>你无法从这些内容中看懂任何信息，但是，你很幸运，你并不是第一个试图看懂它们的人。然而不论之前是谁阅读了这些文件，那位博学的人制作了一些关于文件内容的草图，看起来像是描述一些藏有稀有服装和盔甲的地点！你把这些文件安全地藏在箱子里，只待你有时间来更仔细地研究它们</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e56_v6wf</Cell><Cell>A legend is circulating in the province about stashes containing magnificent Warhorse armour. Many people have searched for it, but in vain. With a little effort and the grace of God, perhaps you can succeed in finding the armour and donning it to assist you in fighting the good fight!</Cell><Cell>一个代代相传的传说提到在这片地区的一些宝箱里，存放着伟大的战马盔甲。很多人都去找了，但无一成功。在上帝的眷顾和自己的努力下，也许你可以找到这些盔甲，并在日后的战斗中成为你坚不可摧的护盾！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e58_tSzl</Cell><Cell>The first part of the Warhorse armour and five treasure maps will appear in your universal trunk after launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; in Rattay Mill. You can access your trunk from any home or lodgings you have in the world.</Cell><Cell>战马盔甲最初的一部分和五张藏宝图会在您开始主线任务 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 后在您拉泰城的储存箱里出现。您可以在全世界任何一个您的家里或者租的旅店访问您的箱子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch2_HvqS_e60_b6T9</Cell><Cell>The first part of the Warhorse armour and five more treasure maps are stored in your universal trunk in Rattay Mill. You can access your trunk from any home or lodgings you have in the world.</Cell><Cell>战马盔甲最初的一部分和五张藏宝图会在您拉泰城的储存箱里出现。您可以在全世界任何一个您的家里或者租的旅店访问您的箱子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e29_B18G</Cell><Cell>Although you hardly ventured beyond Skalitz your whole life, now and again you heard tidings from travelling merchants and wayfarers about goings on in the outside world - the big harvest festival in Merhojed, the rebuilding of Sasau Monastery and stories about an abandoned village in the woods near Talmberg. </Cell><Cell>尽管你这辈子都几乎没出过斯卡里茨，你时不时地会听到一些旅行商人和旅人们说起外面的世界——莫霍杰德的大丰收节、重建了的莎邵修道院，和一个塔尔木堡附近森林中的废弃村庄的故事。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e30_zOG0</Cell><Cell>That village is called Pribyslavitz, and for years it has lain in ruins. You've always been curious about it - where exactly it is, what mysteries it conceals and why no one ever went back there to live. You're determined to go there and explore the village, just as soon as you and the local lords have dealt with the bandits.</Cell><Cell>那个村子叫普拉比西拉维奇，已经荒废多年了。你一直都对它很好奇——它在哪，它掩藏着什么秘密，又为什么从来没人回去居住呢？你决定要去那村子探索一番，你跟当地的大人们解决完匪徒们之后立刻就去。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e32_eqgM</Cell><Cell>After you and your comrades-in-arms drove the bandits out of Pribyslavitz, the village was once again left to be slowly swallowed up by the woods. A shame - before being plundered by a renegade lord, it was no doubt a sprawling, bustling hamlet, judging by the size of the ruined church there, which is all that's left as a reminder of its former prosperity.</Cell><Cell>当你和你的同僚们把匪徒们从普拉比西拉维奇赶跑之后，村子又一次恢复了平静，等待着被森林再次吞没。真是遗憾——在被一个叛变的领主掠夺过之前，它也曾是个生机蓬勃、人丁兴旺的村子，这一点能够从教堂废墟的规模看出来。那废墟是曾经的繁荣景象所遗留下来的唯一证明了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e33_mdnB</Cell><Cell>You always wondered why the folk never went back to live there, so you were pleasantly surprised to learn that Sir Divish has plans for his former hamlet. You don't know exactly what he has in mind, but you'll be glad to have a hand in it. You're sure to find out in Talmberg what needs to be done.</Cell><Cell>你一直都很好奇为什么从来都没人回去住，所以当你知道戴卫斯大人对他曾经的村庄的计划之后很是惊喜。你不知道他到底有什么主意，但你很乐意帮他一把。你会在塔尔木堡了解到你该做什么的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e41_Z7m2</Cell><Cell>Pribyslavitz, a sprawling, long-abandoned village, is now swallowed up by the woods. You always wondered what secrets it concealed and why the villagers never returned there, and so you were pleasantly surprised when Sir Divish told you he had plans for the old settlement. </Cell><Cell>普拉比西拉维奇，一个被废弃了很久的小村庄，现在正在被森林吞噬。你一直好奇这里埋藏着怎样的秘密，为什么村民们不回来？所以在戴卫斯大人告诉你他对这片就遗迹有所规划时，你很开心</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e43_Sx5N</Cell><Cell>Sir Divish enlists your help in rebuilding Pribyslavitz after the bandits have been driven out of the hamlet in the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Baptism of Fire.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. However, you will temporarily not be able to launch or continue playing the DLC during any battle quests.</Cell><Cell>戴卫斯大人希望你可以帮忙重建在主线任务 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Baptism of Fire.&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 里与土匪激战的普拉比西拉维奇村。如果你不确定怎么去找他，请找找 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt 标志。然而，如果你现在正在进行任何战斗任务，你都不可以开始或者继续游玩DLC内容</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch4_3oGW_e45_P5pu</Cell><Cell>Go and see Sir Divish, who wants you to help rebuild Pribyslavitz.  If you're not sure where to find him, look for the &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt; icon. Bear in mind, though, that it will not be possible to temporarily resume or complete the rebuilding during any battles. </Cell><Cell>去找戴卫斯大人，他想重建普拉比西拉维奇。如果你不确定怎么去找他，请找找 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc1Overlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt 标志。请注意，在任何战斗中都无法暂停或完成重建工作</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch5_mZpP_e507_HUZ7</Cell><Cell>A few days later.</Cell><Cell>几天之后。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e11_xZNi</Cell><Cell>You can get a dog from Theresa at Rattay Mill, but only after launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>你可以在拉泰的磨坊找到特丽莎并得到一只狗狗，但得在这个主线任务开始之后You can get a dog from Theresa at Rattay Mill, but only after launching the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;初临拉泰&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e13_pa33</Cell><Cell>Theresa's story is now active. You can launch the quest line by talking to Theresa. You'll be led to her by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>特丽莎的故事已经激活，你可以通过与特丽莎对话来开始任务。这个会带你去找到她 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e17_jskP</Cell><Cell>Theresa is now looking after a dog at Rattay Mill. She's hoping you take it over, because her uncle, Miller Peshek, doesn't like the animal. Go and see Theresa and offer to help.</Cell><Cell>特丽莎现在在拉泰的磨坊照顾一只狗狗，她希望你能接替她，因为他的叔叔，皮社科，不喜欢动物。去找特丽莎并帮忙</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e21_BK5Z</Cell><Cell>A difficult fate awaits Johanka. To find out more, go and visit her at the monastery infirmary and look for &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;</Cell><Cell>命运在呼唤乔汉卡。想了解更多的话，请去莎邵修道院的病院找她，请跟随这个 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e3_k92t</Cell><Cell>Armed with fortitude and dignity, she faces the coming days with a smile on her lips. And since God moves in mysterious ways, none of us can know the lot we shall have to bear. But it is often those of whom we least expect it who encounter an extraordinary destiny...</Cell><Cell>用勇气与尊严武装自己，她以微笑面对接下来的几天。介于上帝的指示很难揣测，她的命运我们无法知晓。但很对时候，去做大事的人，却是我们想不到的人物……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e5_oXts</Cell><Cell>You're the son of a blacksmith, whose life centred around the forge, not farming and livestock. It's not as if you ever missed cattle or pigs, but to have a dog of your own? Now that would be nice...</Cell><Cell>你是铁匠之子，人生主要围绕在铁匠铺周围，而不是农田与牲畜。也许可能养不了猪羊了，但狗还是可以的吧？能养的话就好了……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e7_tMbu</Cell><Cell>Theresa's story will be available to you once you launch the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Awakening&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. Then all you have to do is talk to Theresa in Rattay Mill. You'll be led to her by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>特丽莎的任务会在主线任务 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;初临拉泰&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;开始后开放 然后你要做的是和特丽莎在拉泰的磨坊对话。这个会带你去找到她 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4TheresaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap35_sch6_EHtL_e9_AUe9</Cell><Cell>A difficult fate awaits Johanka. To find out more about it, you must have completed the side quests &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Pestilence&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;In God's Hands&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;, whether successfully or not. You will get to &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Pestilence&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; from the main quest &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;Questions and Answers&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;In God's Hands&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; is assigned to you by Johanka, who is to be found at Sasau Monastery. Once you've completed those quests, all you have to do is visit Johanka again, where you will be guided by &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell><Cell>命运在呼唤乔汉卡。想了解更多的话，您必须完成支线任务 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;瘟疫肆虐&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 和 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;听天由命&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;不管你有没有成功完成任务。 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;瘟疫肆虐&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 主线任务 &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;水落石出&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;font color='#B8AE7E'&amp;gt;听天由命&amp;lt;/font&amp;gt; 是乔汉卡给你的任务，你可以在莎邵修道院找到她。一旦你完成了这些任务，你只需要再找乔汉卡一次，这个会带你去找到她 &amp;lt;img src='img://Libs/UI/Textures/Dynamic/dlc4JohankaOverlay.dds' width='38' height='38' align='baseline' vspace='-8' &amp;gt;.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch35_xmhH_e337_KWau</Cell><Cell>Preacher</Cell><Cell>牧师</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e13_bdlz</Cell><Cell>Hold-up</Cell><Cell>停下</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e14_Ii0w</Cell><Cell>Don't interfere in it</Cell><Cell>不要干涉</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e18_AlMX</Cell><Cell>Fight</Cell><Cell>战斗</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e19_lmga</Cell><Cell>Watch the battle</Cell><Cell>观战</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e19_velx</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>走为上策</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch42_ZQyf_e23_Onaq</Cell><Cell>Untie</Cell><Cell>解开</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e497_Jylz</Cell><Cell>Carcass on the Road</Cell><Cell>路上有尸体</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e498_udhL</Cell><Cell>Stop</Cell><Cell>停下</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e499_Gkvg</Cell><Cell>Ride around and ignore it</Cell><Cell>无视并骑马绕行</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e500_6K58</Cell><Cell>Go around and ignore it</Cell><Cell>无视并绕行</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e503_wcog</Cell><Cell>Have a chat</Cell><Cell>与其交流</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e504_4I17</Cell><Cell>Flee</Cell><Cell>走为上策</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch44_mS8C_e514_FS5n</Cell><Cell>Look at the weapon</Cell><Cell>查看武器</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch45_nmtr_e95_BhsL</Cell><Cell>Give the convict a drink.</Cell><Cell>给罪犯一口水喝。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch47_94Dl_e1_W2wk</Cell><Cell>Chase</Cell><Cell>追逐</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e1_O1wc</Cell><Cell>Attack on the road</Cell><Cell>路上的袭击</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e16_ewho</Cell><Cell>Scout</Cell><Cell>查看</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e17_PQwb</Cell><Cell>Halt</Cell><Cell>停下</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e18_2dRv</Cell><Cell>Run away</Cell><Cell>溜掉</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chap5_sch50_NV1D_e19_RGfd</Cell><Cell>Avoid</Cell><Cell>避开</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch15_T7No_e6_QlXw</Cell><Cell>Too many of your men have died.</Cell><Cell>我方伤亡惨重</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e11_6IvY</Cell><Cell>The early 15th century was a time of turmoil in the Holy Roman Empire, which had flourished under the late Emperor Charles IV, but now, with his son Wenceslas “the Idle“ on the Bohemian throne, was falling into disarray.</Cell><Cell>十五世纪初的神圣罗马帝国是动荡不安的。她曾在先皇查理四世的治下繁荣过，但现在，波西米亚的王位传给了他昏庸的儿子瓦茨拉夫，帝国也随之陷入了混乱</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e12_U8N0</Cell><Cell>The King’s inactivity angered many of the nobility, as well as his half-brother, King Sigismund of Hungary, who decided to take drastic steps to restore order to the Empire…</Cell><Cell>国王的昏庸激怒了不少王公贵族，包括他同父异母的皇兄，匈牙利之王西格斯蒙德，他选择用极端的方式重整帝国……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e12_vkUl</Cell><Cell>Silver Skalitz, 1403</Cell><Cell>银之斯卡里茨，西历一四零三年（大明永乐元年）</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch2_iRf2_e990_QBhT</Cell><Cell>Throw manure.</Cell><Cell>扔屎</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch22_LAqJ_e810_xbED</Cell><Cell>Skip mass</Cell><Cell>跳过弥撒</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch22_LAqJ_e815_OUNX</Cell><Cell>Eat</Cell><Cell>吃东西</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch25_kJcP_e58_PAkf</Cell><Cell>Raise the portcullis</Cell><Cell>升起门闸！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch25_kJcP_e9_mUC2</Cell><Cell>Before the return to Talmberg</Cell><Cell>返回塔尔木堡之前</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch28_w7oB_e271_IWz9</Cell><Cell>You did not arrive at the battleground.</Cell><Cell>你依然没有抵达战场</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch28_w7oB_e273_wPqw</Cell><Cell>You fled the battlefield.</Cell><Cell>你逃离了战场</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch7_9t19_e58_Suu4</Cell><Cell>In the castle.</Cell><Cell>在城堡里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch7_9t19_e8_Zrcd</Cell><Cell>Run!</Cell><Cell>逃出生天！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch7_nFPk_e311_GKf6</Cell><Cell>Zbyshek killed you while you were unconscious.</Cell><Cell>巴舍克在你失去意识的时候把你杀了</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch8_Votg_e104_iWG2</Cell><Cell>A FEW DELIRIOUS DAYS LATER…</Cell><Cell>昏迷了几天之后……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch8_Votg_e186_2516</Cell><Cell>AND EVEN LATER…</Cell><Cell>然后更晚点……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>chapter1a_sch9_FEsU_e1491_2eLv</Cell><Cell>Inspect</Cell><Cell>四周看看</Cell></Row>
</Table>